Alison Reilly

Miami, FL | reillyamr@gmail.com

Portfolio alisonreilly.dev | LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/alisonreilly | Github github.com/Tsunamins

Full Stack Software Engineer with expertise in React and versatile backend experience across Python, Golang, Java, and Ruby on Rails. Possess critical thinking and need anticipation to enhance enterprise solutions and customer experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

TypescriptReactJavaPythonRedisSeleniumJestJavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer I – Parchment, an Instructure Company | Remote

9/2022 – present

- Developed a React and TypeScript component library, ensuring UI consistency and improving development speed
- Enhanced application reliability and safeguarded future changes writing unit tests with React Testing Library and Jest
- Modernized legacy code on full stack teams, integrating component library with corresponding API revisions
- Created API endpoints with Spring Boot, optimizing data access and reducing boilerplate with Hibernate and Lombok
- Managed schema changes with Liquibase, ensuring seamless integration and data consistency

Software Engineer I – American Express | Remote

12/2021 – 9/2022

- Created front-end features for an internal use automations platform using React and the company design library
- Built API endpoints in Golang and Python (Flask) with a focus on reporting solutions, increasing team impact
- Enhanced endpoint processing times by integrating a Redis Client, optimizing reporting and other critical functionalities
- Added automated UI testing with GitLab pipeline Selenium tests, enhancing platform robustness and reliability
- Co-hosted meetings to demonstrate product, facilitate onboarding, enhancing platform adoption and understanding

Technical Support Engineer – **ServiceNow** | Remote

3/2021 - 12/2021

- Diagnosed and corrected client/server issues through Chrome Dev Tools and platform-specific debugging
- Analyzed code changes in version control tools to provide accurate and informed support
- Optimized and suggested platform settings, security rules and table functions, optimizing workflow experience
- Accelerated ticket resolution by coordinating with customers, team and developers, streamlining problem-solving
- Authored and updated knowledge base articles, driving self-service support and reducing recurring customer inquiries

Backend Developer Intern - 1909 | Remote

8/2020 - 03/2021

- Built middleware using Node.js and Firebase to integrate OfficeRnd and Salesforce APIs
- Implemented webhook routing with Express.js for efficient data handling and clear separation of concerns
- Synced goals bi-weekly with the product owner and team, ensuring alignment and progress.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School - Software Engineering

6/2020

Bootcamp with concentrations on Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React

Additional Coursework - LaGuardia Community College

3/2013 - 08/2017

■ Relevant Courses: Intro to Computer Science, Advanced C++, Pre-calculus, Calculus I

AFFILIATIONS AND VOLUNTEERING

CodePath.org – Coach and Community Member

6/2024 - present

Mentor and coach students for technical interview prep in Python. Ongoing community member.